Just exactly is a rain stick ?
Who makes rain sticks?
And How are they made?
Well this is a rain stick and rain sticks are made by people in Africa , they were made by the Aztecs, they are made by Native American and this particular rain stick was made by the Deaquitrix Tribe, people who live in Chile, just below the Andes mountains.
How are real rains sticks made? People take a cactus that has died and has fallen down and while it is still soft, or just beginning to dry out they'll cut it into sticks the lengths they want, then as you can see here the thorns of the cactus are pulled off and turned around and pushed back into the cactus, all along the cactus, in holes that are naturally.
These spiral down or go up and down depending on the type of cactus.
Then the cactus is put in the sun to dry and a piece of the cactus is put in the bottom to seal it.
Then the cactus is filled with something natural, this particular rain stick is filled with little pebbles.
I know that Native Americans, in the south west of Arizona make rain sticks and fill them with the seeds of the cactus.
We are going to make rain sticks too, and if we are not fortunate enough to have a piece of cactus laying around there are other things we can use.
So won't you join me make a rain stick?